# **Christy Yiran Chen**

## 647-936-7015 | christychen65@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Highly skilled and experienced professional with a proven track record of delivering business intelligence solutions across diverse industries, including financial services, corporate finance, retail banking, marketing and CRM. Possesses a deep understanding of DW, with a strong ability to analyze, present complex data in a simple and meaningful way.

# **Core Competency**

- ✓ Financial Reporting
- ✓ Customer Transaction
- ✓ Business Requirement
- ✓ Marketing Campaign
- ✓ Budget & Forecasting

- ✓ BI: Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics,
- ✓ Reporting Automation
- ✓ Snowflake, Databricks, SAS, Azure Data Factory
- ✓ TSQL, Python, SparkSql, PySpark, R, Access, Excel VBA
- ✓ **Jira**, Confluence, ServiceNow, draw.io

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Consultant, Cloud Implementation | EDPYPF Services Incorporated.

Mar 2023 - Present

- Presented Snowflake Environment PoC for management evaluation of Data Warehouse platform.
- ♦ Integrated Azure ADF, Function, and Power BI with Snowflake, enabling seamless data flow.
- ♦ Converted TSQL procedures to Snowflake procedures for smooth migration.
- ♦ Conducted data profiling and gap analysis, leveraging customer behavior data in Snowflake.
- Created semantic views for comprehensive understanding of customer behavior data.

#### Data Analyst Intern, Marketing Analytics | EDPYPF Services Incorporated.

Sep 2022 – Mar 2023

- Delivered 2 comprehensive BRDs by gathering requirements, identifying KPIs, and providing detailed specifications
- Improved campaign targeting accuracy by 10% through PBI customer segmentation dashboards
- Developed **customer migration dashboard** with 9M+ transactions, improving business monitoring.
- Achieved 10% YoY cost savings through trending, comparison & top-n analyses via an expense control dashboard
- ♦ Conducted business analyses on <u>sales performance</u>, Campaign, subscription, market share and competitors
- Improved reconciliation accuracy by 30% through test planning, case design, scripting and issue tracking

#### Analyst Intern | ZGC Smart City Co. Ltd

Oct 2021 – Aug 2022

- Automated department-level Access & Excel reporting, improving efficiency by 85%.
- Delivered Monthly **Financial Income Statement** report design, automation and publishing to Database using VBA.
- Visualized & cleaned patients' relationships data via Neo4j & MySQL to prevent infection chain expansion
- Extracted, transformed and loaded 200k+ Real Estate data daily into PostgreSQL DB using Python
- ♦ Created **daily summary dashboard** of average 50+ reported cases for Patients Contract Tracker project.

#### **Investment Analyst Intern | Galaxy Securities**

May 2021 – Jul 2021

- Designed financial research questionnaire and presented key findings at weekly consumer review meeting.
- Collected and analyzed financial market data from multiple sources in Excel and R to extract insights.
- ♦ Conducted **regression analyses** to identify **correlations** between sales data, stock market index & consumers.
- Submitted analysis report on REIT "First Listing Day" by analyzing a 3GB Wind financial data.

# Customer Representative | HUAXIA Bank | Kunming, China

Jul 2020 – Sep 2020

Advised 100+ clients on LPR conversion and assisted with **credit card** applications, recommending tailored financial products to fulfill their financial needs, such as **GIC**, **Mortgage** and **trading** related.

## **ACDEMIC PROJECTS**

- ♦ Bella beat Smart Device Marketing Strategy Analyses & Visualization (GitHub)
- Market Share Analysis Big Buy Retail Sales (GitHub)
- Business Case for The Source Prepaid Acceleration through self-stores vs. Third Party Store (GitHub)

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science**, Statistics & Economics

# **University of Toronto**

Sep 2017 - May 2021

Coursework: Data Analysis, Introduction to Computer Programming, Method Data Analysis, Financial Economics

**Certificates:** 1- Google Analytics Advanced - Digital Marketing Campaign KPI Analyses (Dec 2022) | 2- Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python (May 2022) | 3- Forage KPMG Data Analytics Consulting Virtual Internship (2022)